readmill.com 2014-03-28

# Privacy Policy - Readmill

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, store, use and disclose your personal information when you use the website, our mobile app, related widgets and API provided by Readmill (together, the “Platform”).

This Privacy Policy sets out the terms on which Readmill Network Limited (“Readmill”, “We”, “Us”) collects personal data. Your privacy is very important to us. Accordingly, we have developed this Policy in order for you to understand how we collect, use, communicate, disclose and make use of personal information.

This Privacy Policy explains the following, amongst other things:

  * Our principles with respect to your data and your privacy
  * The information we collect about you
  * How we use your personal information
  * How we share your personal information
  * Your choices with respect to your personal information
  * How to contact us regarding privacy issues

If you do not agree to any of the provisions of this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Website, the Apps or any of the Services. If you have any questions or concerns, you can contact us at [support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com).

We have a simple approach to data protection and privacy, which can be summarized as follows:

## You should know exactly what we do with your data

This Privacy Policy is designed to give you full transparency regarding our data protection practices. If there’s anything that’s not clear from this Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com)

## You should have full control over your data

We’ve designed the Website to give you control over the information you publish and share using Readmill and other sites and services to which you connect your Readmill account. Please take full advantage of these tools and make sure you only share what you want to share.

## Information we collect about you

Personal Data will only be collected for the purpose of providing our Websites functions, unless you expressly consent to other uses.

We may collect data in an anonymous form and use this data in order to improve our services. We collect personal information about you from various sources:

### Information provided by you

  * Essential Information: When you register any kind of Readmill account, you will need to provide your email address and choose a password.
  * Profile Information: You may choose, at your discretion, to provide additional information for your public profile on Readmill, for example: 
    * Your real name
    * A user name (which may be your real name or a pseudonym)
    * The city and country in which you live
    * A profile picture or avatar
  * Information about how you categorize yourself with respect to content
  * Details of your other websites and social media profiles, including links to those websites and profiles

None of this profile information is mandatory, and any information you do provide may be deleted, edited, changed or amended by you at any time. For more information, see the Choice and Control section below.

  * Information from Correspondence: You will provide certain personal information if you contact us by email, or contact us by mail or other offline means.
  * Survey Information: If you participate in any survey, you will provide certain personal information as part of your response, unless you respond anonymously.
  * Information that you post: You may provide personal information when you upload readings to the Platform, or when you post comments, or contribute to community discussions.

### Information we collect automatically

There is certain information that we collect automatically as the result of your use of the Platform, or through the use of web analytics services. This information includes:

  * The Internet Protocol (IP) address of the device from which you access the Platform (this can sometimes be used to derive the country or city from which you are accessing the Platform)
  * The site you visited immediately prior to visiting the Website
  * The specific actions that you take on the Platform, including but not limited to the pages that you visit, connecting your Facebook or Twitter account, following or unfollowing another user, posting a comment, or performing a search
  * Any search terms that you may enter on the Website
  * The time, frequency and duration of your visits to the Platform
  * The nature of the device from which you are accessing the Platform, for example, whether you are accessing the Platform from a personal computer or from a mobile device
  * Information regarding your interaction with email messages, for example, whether you opened, clicked on, or forwarded the email message

### Information from Other Sources

#### Facebook

Readmill allows you to sign up and log in using your Facebook account. If you sign up using Facebook, Facebook will ask your permission to share certain information from your Facebook account with Readmill. This includes your first name, last name, gender, general location, a link to your Facebook profile, your time zone, birthday, profile picture, your "likes" and your list of friends.

This information is collected by Facebook and is provided to us under the terms of Facebook’s privacy policy. You can control the information that we receive from Facebook using the privacy settings in your Facebook account.

If you sign up to Readmill using Facebook, your Readmill account will be connected automatically to your Facebook account. If you do not wish to share your Readmill activity with your Facebook friends, you can control this from the Settings page on the Website.

## How we use your personal information

The Personal Data will only be processed and used for the purpose of providing our Websites functions, unless you expressly consent to other uses.

We use the information that we collect about you for the following purposes:

  * Your email address and password are used to identify you when you log into the Platform.
  * Any additional information that you provide as part of your public profile, such as your real name, and links to your website and other social media profiles (but not your email address), will be published on your profile page. This information will be publicly accessible and may be viewed by anyone accessing the Website, or using our API or other Services. Please bear this in mind when considering whether to provide any additional information about yourself.
  * Your email address will be used to send you service updates and notifications regarding your account, and (if you have elected to receive them using your account preferences) newsletters, marketing messages and certain email notifications. For information about how to change your preferences, and to unsubscribe from newsletters, marketing messages and email notifications, please see the notifications tab in settings on your Readmill profile.
  * If you are a Facebook user, and one of your Facebook friends registers for a Readmill account, we will suggest to your Facebook friend that you might be someone they may wish to follow on Readmill.
  * If you are a Facebook user and sign up using Facebook, we may also use the information we receive about you from Facebook to suggest or connect you to users that you may wish to follow on Readmill. It will be up to you if you choose to follow these users and you can unfollow them at any time.

## Your personal information is also used for the following general purposes

  * To operate and maintain your Readmill account, and to provide you with access to the Website and use of the Apps and any Services that you may request from time to time.
  * To identify you as the creator of content that you share, the comments that you post and/or the other contributions that you make to the Platform.
  * To seek your participation in surveys, and to conduct and analyze the results of those surveys if you choose to participate.
  * To provide you with technical support
  * To provide other users with data regarding people downloading their content
  * To analyze the use of the Platform, and the people visiting the Website and using the Apps and Services, in order to improve Readmill.
  * To respond to you about any comment or enquiry you have submitted.
  * To customize your use of the Platform and/or the content of any email newsletter or other material that we may send to you from time to time like book recommendation emails or recommended people to follow, for example.
  * To prevent or take action against activities that are, or may be, in breach of our Terms of Service, Community Guidelines or applicable law.
  * For other purposes, provided we disclose this to you at the relevant time, and provided that you agree to the proposed use of your personal information.

## Cookies

We use so-called “Cookies” for the purpose of making our services more user-friendly, more effective and safer. For detailed information on the cookies we use and how we use them, see our Cookie Policy at [readmill.com/pages/cookie-policy](http://readmill.com/pages/cookie-policy).

## Google Analytics

Readmill uses Google Analytics, service for the marketing analysis of this website, of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses codes consisting of text and numbers, which will be stored on your computer and which allow for an analysis of the use of the Websites (“Cookies”). The information generated by the Cookie about your use of the Websites (including your IP address) will be transferred to and stored by a Google Server. Google will use this information, to evaluate your use of the website, to prepare reports about the website activities for the website operators and to provide further services connected to the use of websites and the use of the Internet. Google may transfer this information to third parties, if legally obliged to do so or if third parties process these data on behalf of Google. In no case, Google will connect your IP address with other data from Google.

You can remove or deactivate such Cookies using the settings of your computer; in such a case you might not be able to fully use all functions of this website. By using this website you agree to the processing of your Personal Data by Google to the extent and purpose stated above. You can refuse to allow your data to be passed on by using a deactivation add-on for browsers under <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

Please note that our Websites uses Google Analytics with the extension `_anonymizelp()` and consequently IP addresses are only used in shortened form in order to prevent direct personal references.

## Kissmetrics

We use Kissmetrics, a web analytics service provided by Space Pencil, Inc. (“Kissmetrics”). The service puts first-party cookies on your computer which allow for the analysis of the use of this website. No permanent, resurrected or third-party cookies are being used. Information generated by the cookies will be transferred to and saved on a server of the analysis service provider. Together with the aforementioned information IP-addresses will be transferred to the service provider.

Any information is cleared when you clear your browser cookies. You can opt out by using the Do Not Track header: Kissmetrics will not record any information about the people who have enabled it.

Alternatively, you can disable KISSmetrics at any time, by clicking on the Button “OPT OUT OF KISSmetrics TRACKING” which is available at: <http://www.kissmetrics.com/user-privacy>. KISSmetrics will then place a Cookie to stop further recording. Please note that if you delete your Cookies, then this will also delete the Cookie, which stops recording and you will have to reset it.

## New Relic

We use the New Relic service provided by New Relic, Inc., to monitor the performance of the website, it’s underlying systems and architecture.

See the following link for further information:

<https://newrelic.com/docs/general/what-cookiesdoes-newrelic-create>

## Consent to the use of personal data

I hereby consent to the collection, processing and use of the personal data, i.e. first name, last name, email address, IP address and company name (“Personal Data”) which will be passed to

New Relic, 188 Spear Street, Suite 1200, San Francisco, CA 94105 USA (“New Relic”) and saved on New Relic’s server.

I can withdraw these consents and opt-out of having information collected by or submitted to New Relic at any time by emailing [support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com)

## Sharing of your personal information

We will not share your personal information with any third party, except as described in this Privacy Policy. There are circumstances where we may need to share some of the personal information we collect about you or which you provide to us - these circumstances are as follows:

  * Partner publishers and authors: Any personal information in your public profile (other than your email address) will be accessible by other users of the Platform, who may view your profile information, read and comment on any of your readings, add themselves to your list of followers, and send you messages. If you read content from a partner publisher or author, the fact that you have read that content and how your read it (including the device, time, progress, location, and sharing activity) may be shared, on a purely anonymous basis, with that publisher or author so that they can track the engagement of their content. Similarly, if you publicly comment on any readings on the Platform, your comments will be available to all users of the Platform.
  * With your consent: We will disclose your personal information if you have explicitly agreed that we may do so.
  * Users of our API: Readmill has an open API which enables application developers to integrate elements of the Platform into exciting new apps. Some of these developers may be locations outside of the European Economic Area. Any personal information that you choose to make public on the Platform, including our public profile information and any public readings, may be accessible to these developers. Please bear this in mind when deciding what information to publish on your profile.
  * Other networks and connected apps: If you choose to connect your Readmill account to other apps or social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Wordpress or Pinterest, you will be sharing certain information with these apps or networks. Readmill is not responsible for these other apps or networks, so please make sure you only connect your account with apps or services that you trust. For information on how to control the information that your share, and how to disconnect your account from other networks or apps, please see the Connection tab in your profile.
  * Other networks and connected apps: If you choose to connect your Readmill account to other apps or social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr, Wordpress or Pinterest, you will be sharing certain information with these apps or networks. Readmill is not responsible for these other apps or networks, so please make sure you only connect your account with apps or services that you trust. For information on how to control the information that your share, and how to disconnect your account from other networks or apps, please see the Connection tab in your profile.
  * As aggregated data: We may aggregate your personal data with similar data relating to other users of the Platform in order to create statistical information regarding the Platform and its use, which we may then share with third parties or make publicly available. However, none of this information would include any email address or other contact information, or anything that could be used to identify you individually, either online or in real life.
  * If required by law: We will disclose your personal information if we believe in good faith that we are permitted or required to do so by law, including in response to a court order, subpoena or other legal demand or request.
  * To protect our interests: We may disclose your personal information if we feel this is necessary in order to protect or defend our legitimate rights and interests, or those of our users, employees, directors or shareholders, and/or to ensure the safety and security of the Platform and/or the Readmill community.
  * In the context of a business transfer: We may transfer your personal information to any person or company that acquires all or substantially all of the assets or business of Readmill, or on a merger of our business, or in the event of our insolvency.

## Choice and Control

We do our best to give you as much choice as possible regarding the amount of personal information you provide to us, and the control you have over that information.

It is not necessary for you to provide us with any information in order to visit the Website, although certain information will be collected automatically by virtue of your visit (as described above). However, if you do decide to register a Readmill account, you can control your personal information in the following ways.

### Email preferences

Check out the Basics tab within your Settings page on the Website. When you are logged in to your account, you can access your Settings by clicking on your profile picture at the top of the screen, and selecting Settings from the drop down menu.

From the Basics tab you can tell us:

  * The email address that you may wish us to use to communicate with you.

You can also turn off email notifications from the Notifications tab within your Settings. This will immediately disable all email notifications, other than essential account notifications such as important service updates, reports of copyright infringement and other essential information relating to your account and your use of the Platform.

It is also possible to unsubscribe from email newsletters and notifications (other than essential account notifications) at any time by clicking on the link at the end of each email.

### Sharing with other apps and networks

The Connections tab within your Settings on the Website enables you to control the information you share with other networks and applications. As well as selecting those of your social networks you wish to share to, you can also control access to other services and applications to which you have connected your Readmill account.

If you sign up for Readmill using your Facebook account, your Readmill account and your Facebook account respectively will be connected automatically. Information regarding the public readings, comments and likes that you post on Readmill, will be shared with the connected Facebook account. If you do not want this information shared with Facebook please change your Settings.

Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to any third party sites or applications, and we cannot control the activities of those sites or applications. You are advised to read the privacy policies of those sites or applications before sharing your information with, or connecting your Readmill account to, any of these third party sites or applications.

### Sharing with other users

Readmill is a very social place, but if you would prefer to read anonymously you may do so anytime in the app. By doing so, other users will not be able to see your readings, but we will still have access to this information.

### Sharing with app developers

Readmill has an open API, which allows third party developers to build some really cool apps as an extension of the Platform. Please note that your public profile information will be accessible, but this does not include anything that this not publicly available on the Website.

### Deleting your account

You can delete your account from the Basics page within your Settings on the Website at any time. Please bear in mind that, if you delete your account, all data associated with your account, including the content shared and the usage data associated with that content, will be deleted and may not be recoverable. You are therefore advised to copy or back up all content uploaded to your account before you delete your account.

Even if you delete your Readmill account, it is possible that your information may still show up in some internet search results for a short while afterwards, if the search engine maintains a temporary cache of web pages. Search engines' caching processes are outside of Readmill’s control and therefore we cannot be responsible for any information that remains cached by search engines after that information has been removed from the Platform.

Please note that deleting any Readmill Apps, or any third party apps to which your Readmill account is connected, will not delete your Readmill account. If you wish to delete your account, you will need to do so from the Basics tab in your Settings on the Website. Similarly, if you delete a third party app that is connected to your Readmill account over our API, this will not necessarily delete all data from within that third party app. You will need to refer to the app provider’s terms of use and privacy policy to find out how to delete your data from that third party app.

## Access to your data

As described above, most of the personal information you provide to us can be accessed and updated in the Settings page of your Readmill account. If you wish to access, amend or delete any other personal information we hold about you, or if you have any objection to the processing of any information that we hold about you, please contact us at [support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com)

If you ask us to delete your account (either via the Settings page or by email), we will do so within a reasonable period of time, but we may need to retain some of your personal information in order to satisfy our legal obligations, or where we have a legitimate reason for doing so.

## International data transfers

Readmill is based in Europe, and your personal information is collected, stored, used and shared in accordance with European laws. However, from time to time, it may be necessary for us to transfer your personal data to the United States to (1) maintain a high level of service through companies like New Relic, (2) provide useful information to you relating to the app and website through services like Campaign Monitor and (3) to consistently improve the services and product we offer and you expressly consent to such transfers. You should be aware that privacy laws in the United States may not be equivalent to the laws in your country, and by using the Platform, you consent to the transfer, storage and processing of your personal information in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable law. In relation to such personal data, we shall take all reasonably necessary steps to ensure that it is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Declaration of Consent

I hereby give permission for my personal data to be transferred to third parties as set forth under this Section for the purpose of conducting the services provided by Readmill. I reserve the right to withdraw this consent by notifying Readmill in writing or by e-mail ([support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com)), in which case Readmill will be obligated to delete my personal data from their and the third party’s server within a reasonable period of time.

## Social Plugins

Our website uses the following social plugins (“Plugins”):

  1. Plugin provided by the social network facebook.com, operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). The Plugin is identifiable by a Facebook logo.
  2. Plugin by the Twitter service, operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA (“Twitter”). The button can be recognized via the “Twitter” or “Follow” sign.
  3. The content of the Plugin button is sent directly from the relevant company (e.g. Facebook) to your browser and integrated via the browser into the webpage. This may have the effect of establishing a direct connection between your browser and the servers of the respective companies (e.g. Facebook) as soon as you visit a page of our website that contains the Plugin. Further or more intensive interaction usually occurs when you press the relevant buttons (e.g. by clicking “Like” in case of Facebook), especially if you are simultaneously logged onto the services of the respective companies. Our own website can therefore not influence which data is collected through the operation of the Plugins.
  4. For further information on the collection and processing and use of Personal Data by the respective companies, please visit their websites and view their privacy policies.

## Children

Readmill is not intended for use by children. Anyone under the age of 13 is not permitted to use the Platform and must not attempt to register an account or submit any personal information to us. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from any person who is under the age of 13 or allow them to register an account. If it comes to our attention that we have collected personal data from a person under the age of 13, we will delete this information as quickly as possible. If you have reason to believe that we may have collected any such data, please notify us immediately at [support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com)

## Access to Information

Under EU data protection legislation, you have the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the legislation. Any access request may be subject to a fee of 10 EUR to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

## Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy, and when we do so, we will also revise the Effective Date set out below. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will always be available here so that Readmill users are always aware of what information we gather, and how we might use and share that information. Please be sure to check back here from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes to this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be communicated to registered users by a notification to their account and/or by posting a notice of the change on the Website.

If you have any more questions regarding privacy and data, please contact our team at [support@readmill.com](mailto:support@readmill.com) or send us a tweet [@readmill](http://twitter.com/readmill).

## Responsible Body for Data Protection

The data controller or responsible body within the meaning of the applicable data protection laws is

Readmill Network Limited  
Berlin branch  
10435 Berlin  
Germany
